

# RAJEEV SINGH

Senior Project Engineer

07834939963

rsbrajeevsingh98@gmail.com

Linkedin.com/in/rajeev-singh-8a3542243

#### **EDUCATION**

M.Tech in Computing Systems & Infrastructure **BITS PILANI WILP** 

2020 - 2024

**B.SC (H) Instrumentation University of Delhi** 2017 - 2020

#### **EXPERTISE**

- SCCM / MECM
- SCOM
- PowerShell
- Wintel Patching
- Service now
- Centreon
- VMware vCenter
- Wintel Admin
- Microsoft excel

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Cloud Azure Admin L1
- Cloud Oracle Infrastructure Admin L1
- Google Gen Al

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Inspiring Performance 2023
- Inspiring Performance 2022

#### **PROFILE**

"Dedicated and detailed-oriented professional with expertise in SCCM and Wintel patch management. Committed professional with a strong work ethic, known for ensuring quality and reliability in all tasks. I bring a proactive approach to my work, consistently focused on delivering results and maintaining high standards in any environment."

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Wipro Technologies | S&P GLOBAL

2022 - Present

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Working as a System Administrator, supported IHS Markit Ltd. financial information and analytical company that merged in 2022 with S&P Global.

Headquarter in New York, USA.

Key responsibilities.

- Ensure the servers with compliance with Security Patching/application deployments through SCCM
- Monitoring & resolving Centreon alerts & incidents winthin SLA.
- Maintain servers Inventory for servers, Application, Storage, CPU, Memory etc.
- Patching for critical clustered/Highly available SQL Servers and ensure Replication issue are mitigated through SCCM

#### **Wipro Technologies | STATESTREET**

2020 - 2022

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Working as a System Administrator for State Street Corporation, an American financial services and bank holding company. Headquarter in Boston, USA

#### Key responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting Windows, AD, SQL related issues.
- Monitoring SCOM alerts & incidents and cleared within
- Ensure the servers with compliance with Security
- Patching/application deployments through PowerShell.
- Managing SCOM infrastructure, Implementing Rules & Monitor Alerts
- Troubleshooting Windows, AD server, patching related issues.